The world is a stage.
Joker: Folie à Deux is a drama, crime, thriller film directed by Todd Phillips.
While struggling with his dual identity, Arthur Fleck not only stumbles upon
true love, but also finds the music that's always been inside him.
Arthur Fleck, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Lee Quinzel, played by Lady Gaga.
Jackie Sullivan, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Maryanne Stewart, played by Catherine Keener.
Sophie Dumond, played by Zazie Beetz.
Paddy Meyers, played by Steve Coogan.
Joker: Folie à Deux is a 2024 American jukebox musical legal drama film directed by Todd Phillips
from a screenplay he co-wrote with Scott Silver, as the sequel to Joker (2019).
Joaquin Phoenix stars as Arthur Fleck / Joker, reprising his role from the
first film, alongside Lady Gaga as Harleen "Lee" Quinzel.
The supporting cast includes Brendan Gleeson, Catherine Keener, Zazie
Beetz, Steve Coogan, Harry Lawtey, and Leigh Gill.
In the film, Arthur awaits trial for his crimes at Arkham State Hospital, where
he develops a romantic relationship with another inmate, Lee.
Although Joker was intended to be a standalone film, its success
at the box-office sparked interest in a sequel.
Warner Bros.
eventually convinced Phillips and Phoenix to return, with more
creative freedom and a significantly greater budget.
The film was announced in June 2022, with Gaga
and Beetz joining later that year.
Principal photography took place in New York City, Los Angeles, and
Belleville, New Jersey, from December 2022 to April 2023.
Joker: Folie à Deux premiered at the 81st Venice International Film Festival on
September 4, 2024, and was released in the United States on October 4.
The film was poorly received by critics and became a box-office bomb,
grossing $208 million on a $190–200 million budget.
Among its seven Golden Raspberry Award nominations, it won Worst Remake,
Rip-off or Sequel and Worst Screen Combo for Phoenix and Gaga.
The film explores themes of asylum, villain,
musical, insane asylum, based on comic.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.